checkmyfile.com 2015-12-07

# Our Privacy Policy - checkmyfile

#### We are firmly committed to keeping your personal details private, even if this means that, sometimes, we may not be able to serve you as quickly as you might wish. We make simple, strong statements about privacy so you can be clear about our commitment to you.

We will **never sell** your email address to anyone.

We will **never disclose** your personal details to anyone unless we have your permission to do so, or if we are compelled to do so by Court Order.

We **do not store** the personal information you provide when you use our Free Credit Score service.

We **do not store** the lifestyle information you provide us when you use our Free Identity Theft Expert System.

You may **opt out** or opt back in to receive our monthly emails at any time. Every monthly email we send contains a simple one-click ability to opt out.

## Cookies

We use a minimal number of cookies to support your use of the checkmyfile website. We classify these as being **Strictly Necessary** , **Performance** , **Referral** or **Advertising** cookies. More information is available below - you can change your settings by clicking the Privacy & Cookies link at the top of the page.

#### Strictly Necessary Cookie Examples

These cookies are always set by us, and never by third parties and are used to facilitate your navigation of the site, and provide features or functionality that you request which are provided by us.

Cookie Name

Provider

Purpose

ASP.NET_SessionId

checkmyfile

Used to manage your session on the site - enabling you to navigate pages and access secure areas. No personal information is stored in this cookie which is automatically destroyed when you log out and close your browser.

CookiePreference

checkmyfile

Required to remember any cookie preferences you set with us, namely your preferences for blocking or showing Performance and/or Referral cookies.

#### Performance Cookie Examples

Set by us, or our trusted suppliers these cookies enable us to identify and resolve issues with our website, and to manage the amount of data that is required to view each page, thereby improving the performance of the website for all users.

Cookie Name

Provider

Purpose

__utma

Google

Used by Google to provide data for their Google Analytics service which provides us with detailed information about how our website is performing, which areas have issues and which are the most popular sections of the site that we would then seek to optimise. The data collected through this service is anonymous - we only permit access to our Google Analytics information to ourselves and to no other third party.  
    
View the [Google Privacy & Cookies Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/).

#### Referral Cookie Examples

These cookies are set by our advertising partners to enable us to track referrals sent to us via their advertising networks, and to reward them for promoting our services accordingly.

Cookie Name

Provider

Purpose

Various

Optimise Media Group

These cookies are set by Optimise Media Group, a market leading UK based affiliate marketing company to record a referral to our website from one of many hundreds of websites who promote our services. No personal information is recorded in these cookies, merely the data required to validate the referral at the checkout.  
    
View the [Optimise Media Group Privacy & Cookies Policy](https://www.optimisemedia.com/website-privacy-policy/).

#### Advertising Cookie Examples

These enable us to remind you about our services when you visit other websites that share a similar audience to ours.

Cookie Name

Provider

Purpose

Various

Google, AdRoll

Advertising cookies enable us to re-advertise our services online to you when you visit websites that show our display advertisements generated via Google Adwords, AdRoll or similar ('Third Party Vendors'. These Third Party Vendors use cookies to serve ads based on your past visits to our website. You can opt out of all such advertising by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page.  
    
View the [Google Privacy & Cookies Policy](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/)  
    
View the [AdRoll Privacy Policy](https://www.adroll.com/about/privacy)

## Privacy Practices

#### How we use your information

Your IP address is used to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. Your IP address is used to help identify you and your search requirements and to gather broad demographic information.

When you register on checkmyfile, we ask you for identification information (such as your name and date of birth), contact information (such as your address, email address amd telephone number) and secret information that you share with us (such as your password). We **do not share** any of this information with any third party, other than for obvious purposes (for example we need to give your name address and date of birth to the credit reference agencies when we search you). We use your telephone number only to contact you in case of payment issues arising on any subscription product you purchase from us.

#### Authentication - ensuring we only provide your data to you

If you choose to use our instant, online authentication system, and if you are making use of our 30 day free trial offer, as a first step in our processes we will seek your credit or debit card details and will pre-authorise your card for the initial payment. Pre-authorisation enables us to help prevent fraud, is one of the many elements of our online authentication process, and ensures that the card details that you have provided are both valid and correct. Pre-authorisation also ensures that your card is good for the initial payment due at the end of the 30 day free trial period, if you do not cancel during the 30 day period. No payment is taken from your card at the time of pre-authorisation, although please note that on online bank statements it may appear as if your card has been debited, even though no money has changed hands. If you wish, you can ask us to request your bank to remove the pre-authorisation simply by emailing us.

If you have either trialled our subscription services, or have purchased a one-off report, we may ask for your driving licence number, National Insurance number, and details about your financial commitments. We use this information to help verify your identity, using a complicated system of validation checks. We never reveal exactly how we do this, as if we did, our methods would soon fall into the hands of criminals, and that would defeat the object. We store the information you give us during the authentication process only for the purposes of fraud prevention. If you do not wish to provide this information, you do not have to do so. Instead, you can be authenticated using our postal 'security key' method, which usually takes one working day and is explained more fully when you buy.

From time to time we may need to authenticate you more carefully. The reason is always to ensure that we are releasing your personal information only to you. We will usually ask you to provide original bank statements or credit card statements addressed to you at both your current and previous addresses. We **do not extract** any information from the statements, all your data is kept confidential whilst being processed and are returned to you after being used to verify your addresses.

#### Postcode based information

Demographic and profile data is also collected at our site. This information is not held on an individual basis. We use this data to tailor your experience at our site, showing content that we think you might be interested in, and displaying the content according to your preferences. For example, we use profile data to help identify lenders who extend credit to people with your credit rating, so that we may advise you and others of our findings. We **do not pass** your personal information to any third party except when under compulsion of law or with your consent to do so.

#### Links to other websites

checkmyfile contains links to other sites. Credit Reporting Agency is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.

#### Online surveys

Our online surveys are optional. The information you provide as an individual respondent is **kept confidential** and is aggregated with all other responses to provide the survey results.

#### Security

checkmyfile has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. These include the issue and use of passwords, powerful encryption and computer firewalls to guard against hacking. From time to time we may have to suspend services whilst we investigate any attempted breach of security. You are also obligated, under the Terms and Conditions you agree to abide by when you use our services, to report any suspected breach to us immediately.

#### Supplementation Information

checkmyfile supplements the information that you provide with information received from third parties, (such as the Royal Mail Postcode Address File, which helps confirm your address).

#### Opt-Out

You have the following options if you do not wish to receive future marketing communications from us. Please note that we are still required to notify you from time to time of any significant changes to our terms and conditions, even after you express a preference not to receive marketing communications.

  1. You can send email to [customer.care@checkmyfile.com](mailto:customer.care@checkmyfile.com)
  2. You can write to us at the following postal address: 

checkmyfile  
Chynoweth House  
Trevissome Park  
Truro  
Cornwall  
TR4 8UN 

#### Correct/Update

This site gives you the following options for changing and modifying information previously provided.

  1. You can log in to your account and send a secure message to a professionally trained Credit Analyst. 
  2. You can send email to [admin@checkmyfile.com](mailto:admin@checkmyfile.com)
  3. You can write to us at the following postal address: 

checkmyfile  
Chynoweth House  
Trevissome Park  
Truro  
Cornwall  
TR4 8UN 

#### Contacting checkmyfile about privacy

  1. you can email our Data Controller, who is also our Operations Director: [ian.carpenter@checkmyfile.com](mailto:ian.carpenter@checkmyfile.com)
  2. you can write to 

Ian Carpenter  
Operations Director  
checkmyfile  
Chynoweth House  
Trevissome Park  
Truro  
Cornwall  
TR4 8UN
